

Vernit Jain

About Me

I am a self-motivated technology loving person with excellent research and reading skills; able to grow positive relationships with people. Can adapt to new technologies almost immediately, avid reader. Know ways around many software to accomplish tasks.

Known for friendly nature and troubleshooting abilities.

+91 9045879597 241, Mithulal, Khatauli, Muzaffarnagar, 251201 vernit.jain1@gmail.com



2014 - 2017

Formal Education

Bachelor of Computer Applications 70%

Pandit DDUMC, Meerut

Choudhary Charan Singh University

2014 CBSE Class XII Aggregate 60%

Golden Heart Academy, Khatauli, Muzzafarnagar

2012 CBSE Class X Aggregate 7.0 CGP

Golden Heart Academy, Khatauli, Muzzafarnagar

2014 Oracle Certification

Meerut, Uttar Pradesh

2015 Core Java

New Delhi, Delhi



Projects

Webbased project to handle the data using Java

It is a project which connect Customer database to our database to transmit the data with encryption and also check some validation on the fly before inserting or updating the data in our database

Gesture Recognition at TCS Initial Learning Prog.

Python based project with two hand gloves, equipped with flex sensors were used to pinpoint fingers bending and python was used to read the values and Tensorflow was used to predict gestures.



Professional Experience

2017 TCS Ignite

Tensor Flow Brain Wave prediction, to tell if a person is concentrating or not.

2015 - Present Freelancer.in

Python Scripting, Grease monkey, iMacros and JavaScript based projects.

2017 - Present Tata Consultancy Services

Currently working with TCS iON as a java and python developer in a team that handles web forms and candidate data using Webservice or API.



Interests And Hobbies

- O Web Browsing
- O Gaming
- O Puzzles
- O Travelling to new places



PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Scripting and Development Java and Python

Scripting and Development

JavaScript and JQuery

Algorithms

791 Points

Best Rank 17,434 (8th November,2015) Gold level in Python and Java Silver level in Problem Solving and Java Script

